<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="assets/xml/rss.xsl" media="all"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>junypr berries</title><link>https://junypr.github.io/junypr-berries/</link><description>musings, manuscripts, and spilled ink</description><atom:link href="https://junypr.github.io/junypr-berries/rss.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"></atom:link><language>en</language><copyright>Contents © 2024 &lt;a href="mailto:alex.e.ding@gmail.com"&gt;Alex Ding&lt;/a&gt; </copyright><lastBuildDate>Wed, 23 Oct 2024 00:39:58 GMT</lastBuildDate><generator>Nikola (getnikola.com)</generator><docs>http://blogs.law.harvard.edu/tech/rss</docs><item><title>New Places, Old Faces</title><link>https://junypr.github.io/junypr-berries/posts/new-places-old-faces/</link><dc:creator>Alex Ding</dc:creator><description>&lt;p&gt;Had dinner with you for the first time in years &lt;br&gt;
and now I see you every week  &lt;br&gt;
perhaps with a banana in hand &lt;br&gt;
perhaps rushing to class &lt;br&gt;
and your hair's shorter now &lt;br&gt;
colors I couldn't imagine &lt;br&gt;
but you give me the same smile &lt;br&gt;
that always makes me smile back&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I know the feeling of your chest against my back&lt;br&gt;
warmth seeping from body to body &lt;br&gt;
the night you crashed in my room &lt;br&gt;
a brief stop on your way home   &lt;br&gt;
when we exposed our hearts in the way  &lt;br&gt;
we only could with each other   &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Perhaps you're going through what I was a year ago &lt;br&gt;
and perhaps the photos I send cannot convince you that you will, &lt;br&gt;
in fact, make it through &lt;br&gt;
but seeing your silhouette emerge from the fog on the bridge  &lt;br&gt;
sharing the view on the terrace &lt;br&gt;
makes me hope that you, too, will &lt;br&gt;
find hope in a place  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You eat yogurt with cantaloupe &lt;br&gt;
ask us how we're doing &lt;br&gt;
like you did so many mornings back in New Mexico &lt;br&gt;
the heat and blazing sun's gone, but  &lt;br&gt;
How could I forget your voice, homecoming queen?   &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the morning you twist on the mattress at the base of my bed &lt;br&gt;
and in an instant I'm taken back to my old room &lt;br&gt;
we stare at the stars and wonder simply how &lt;br&gt;
something that lasted only 39 days  &lt;br&gt;
could be something we miss so dearly.   &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now my room feels a little colder, alone &lt;br&gt;
your presence lingers here, in my heart  &lt;br&gt;
I'll see you again &lt;br&gt;
so much closer &lt;br&gt;
until next time, my friend   &lt;/p&gt;</description><category>poetry</category><category>the beauty of seeing people I haven't see in a long time</category><guid>https://junypr.github.io/junypr-berries/posts/new-places-old-faces/</guid><pubDate>Wed, 23 Oct 2024 00:37:08 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Part-time Father</title><link>https://junypr.github.io/junypr-berries/posts/part-time-father/</link><dc:creator>Alex Ding</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;I was five when you left for the first time. Not the two-week business-trip and visiting-family kind of leaving. Not leaving for good, either. You were there one bleak morning, waving goodbye to me through the security lines, steel-gray suitcase and backpack in hand, then gone. House empty. Peaceful.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At first, you and mother call every night. Then every week. Then almost never. The whispers become more like empty screams and I think I hear the phone ring, my mother not picking up, your voice calling for me, me not picking up. I don’t like hearing the screams. I can’t make out the words, but I know what screaming means.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We visited your Shanghai apartment that summer, and I remember the drip of chocolate-dipped ice cream cones, the fan thinly fighting the heat, the plastic covering of the bed that wasn’t my own. I dreamed that blood was pouring from every pore in my skin that night, into the fabric of a foreign-not-foreign country that I can and can’t call my home.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;I was seven when you made the business arrangement. Half your year here, with us, half your year there, in the country I knew in my blood but had never seen. Part-time father, my brother called it. I didn’t know what part-time meant. Or maybe he didn’t.&lt;/em&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;I draw sketches of you from faded yellow photos, to give when you return. Mother says I’m quite good. A natural-born artist.&lt;/em&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://junypr.github.io/junypr-berries/posts/part-time-father/"&gt;Read more…&lt;/a&gt; (5 min remaining to read)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>a collection of experiences from my life and friend's</category><category>prose</category><category>short story</category><guid>https://junypr.github.io/junypr-berries/posts/part-time-father/</guid><pubDate>Wed, 23 Oct 2024 00:09:25 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Lightning Heartbeat</title><link>https://junypr.github.io/junypr-berries/posts/lightning-heartbeat/</link><dc:creator>Alex Ding</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;I count the space between the &lt;br&gt;
flash and the &lt;br&gt;
boom by  &lt;br&gt;
heartbeats.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;one. &lt;br&gt;
electric-charged late night texts,  &lt;br&gt;
frantic breathing as we listened to the  &lt;br&gt;
rain past the window &lt;br&gt;
curled up in bed, I wrote a letter: &lt;br&gt;
love is a house we build with the one loved --- &lt;br&gt;
I didn't know. did I mean it?  &lt;br&gt;
said I love you because you did   &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;two. you painted rose-gold visions of marriage, but  &lt;br&gt;
wouldn't hold my hand &lt;br&gt;
threw me out of the car into the   &lt;br&gt;
pouring rain without a goodbye  &lt;br&gt;
then came begging on your knees for forgiveness, told me  &lt;br&gt;
I love you  &lt;br&gt;
over and over 'til the words tangled into intractable knots  &lt;br&gt;
because you were just the boy  &lt;br&gt;
who ran from the storm to spare his plastic armor from rust, and you &lt;br&gt;
sacrificed me to the goddess of blind hope   &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://junypr.github.io/junypr-berries/posts/lightning-heartbeat/"&gt;Read more…&lt;/a&gt; (1 min remaining to read)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>leaving</category><category>love</category><category>poetry</category><guid>https://junypr.github.io/junypr-berries/posts/lightning-heartbeat/</guid><pubDate>Wed, 23 Oct 2024 00:03:43 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>The Thing About Sunsets</title><link>https://junypr.github.io/junypr-berries/posts/the-thing-about-sunsets/</link><dc:creator>Alex Ding</dc:creator><description>&lt;p&gt;Each sunset is a fragile fraction of a moment suspended in time like a mote of dust in a sunbeam. 
Each day brings a new palette, daubs of inimitable hand-mixed paint swirls. 
So I grab my camera and fly down the stairs, 
I don't stop to say hello because something inside my chest tells me that this is what matters, 
that I need to be here, 
breath catching in the crisp fall air as I watch the last glimmers of sunlight fade over the Charles 
and burnish the glass skyscrapers of Boston's skyline gold. 
Something within me finds peace as my eyes ascend the gradient of soft pink blushes and orange streaks into the wash of 
cyan above. Something tells me that I must hold onto this the way I cling to the rail's flaking paint. 
Something tells me this beauty will never be repeated.
Whether this moment brings me joy or brings me to my knees, 
whether the shimmer is fool's gold or true, 
I have only this moment. 
Like sunsets, nothing lasts forever. 
What is there to be done but to enjoy it?&lt;/p&gt;</description><category>prose</category><category>random thoughts</category><category>sunsets</category><guid>https://junypr.github.io/junypr-berries/posts/the-thing-about-sunsets/</guid><pubDate>Tue, 22 Oct 2024 23:56:30 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Star-</title><link>https://junypr.github.io/junypr-berries/posts/star-/</link><dc:creator>Alex Ding</dc:creator><description>&lt;p&gt;star-gazing star-struck  &lt;br&gt;
on that starry night I was the  &lt;br&gt;
shooting star burning in your  &lt;br&gt;
atmosphere of dark nights   &lt;br&gt;
bus rides through deserts  &lt;br&gt;
head on your shoulder fits  &lt;br&gt;
last-puzzle-piece-perfect &lt;br&gt;
fingers in your hair  &lt;br&gt;
where soft sharp sand sleeps still, I think  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;star-spun binary dance &lt;br&gt;
thumb across my hand&lt;br&gt;
silent mountain shade &lt;br&gt;
late nights flickering flashlights &lt;br&gt;
dodging cockroaches, grasshoppers &lt;br&gt;
twirl me til we crash &lt;br&gt;
let me forget that we were   &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;star-crossed short-lived &lt;br&gt;
supernova burning &lt;br&gt;
sweets keyboard clicks card-shuffles &lt;br&gt;
endless days, momentary weeks &lt;br&gt;
torn from the star-strewn inky blackness &lt;br&gt;
until we were thrown back   &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;star-struck opportune collision &lt;br&gt;
you picked at rabbit bones &lt;br&gt;
thought I could lace my fingers through yours &lt;br&gt;
keep your hand on my waist through  &lt;br&gt;
Madrid mornings Ronda  &lt;br&gt;
sunsets Alhambra sunrises home to the  &lt;br&gt;
pond-side park bench where I watch  &lt;br&gt;
coots feed their young, alone   &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;so I look to the sky and ask &lt;br&gt;
do you see the same &lt;br&gt;
stars we saw in New Mexico?&lt;/p&gt;</description><category>astronomy</category><category>love</category><category>things I write because I need to</category><guid>https://junypr.github.io/junypr-berries/posts/star-/</guid><pubDate>Sun, 06 Oct 2024 02:02:32 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Cloudstrider</title><link>https://junypr.github.io/junypr-berries/posts/cloudstrider/</link><dc:creator>Alex Ding</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;It started with a dying woman.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;She stared from the hemp hammock with silver eyes matching mine. Except there wasn’t a star burning within, just the leaden shine of the three moons through the hut’s reed roof. She resembled me, it was true. The same abyssal hair flecked with stars, the same galaxial swirls dancing across her skin. Even the same flowing robes licked with violet flames, woven from the gasps of a dying star.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;The villager with the sun-washed chest and shell-bead necklace smiled. “She told us to expect you.”&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;“Expect me?”&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It started with darkness.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It’s dark in the space between the stars. It’s dark, and it’s cold, and it’s empty, and it’s where I go to clear my head. I float, where time and space freeze, watching the planets hum their endless melodies, watching newborn stars gasp their first breaths or dying ones scream their last. When I tire of the infinite lights, I close my eyes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My name is Eva Cloudstrider, I mold the fabric of space and time, and I don’t know why I’m here. Maybe if I listen long enough, I’ll find out.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All I hear is a scream. A scream that winds around me until I’m caught in its embrace. A scream that tugs, ever stronger, until I take a step and time spins and spools and falls away. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’m on a beach. The sand like stars again skin darker than the end of time, the waves a kiss upon milky cheeks. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The scream is louder.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The scream is death.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://junypr.github.io/junypr-berries/posts/cloudstrider/"&gt;Read more…&lt;/a&gt; (9 min remaining to read)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>fantasy</category><category>things I write because I can</category><category>time travel</category><guid>https://junypr.github.io/junypr-berries/posts/cloudstrider/</guid><pubDate>Sun, 06 Oct 2024 01:57:31 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>What makes a home</title><link>https://junypr.github.io/junypr-berries/posts/what-makes-a-home/</link><dc:creator>Alex Ding</dc:creator><description>&lt;p&gt;You aren't good at showing it and honestly &lt;br&gt;
neither am I, so I  &lt;br&gt;
choose to write for the moment when  &lt;br&gt;
you return to a house &lt;br&gt;
that will be empty for months as soon as I step &lt;br&gt;
out the door with my luggage kissing this &lt;br&gt;
barren place one last  &lt;br&gt;
good-riddance because it's really not the  &lt;br&gt;
bone-white walls or the  &lt;br&gt;
endless steps or the  &lt;br&gt;
infinite mirrors &lt;br&gt;
I'll miss, because these things don't &lt;br&gt;
make a house home.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I don't say it anymore, really, but I  &lt;br&gt;
love you and I&lt;br&gt;
will miss you when I &lt;br&gt;
fall asleep on top of a plastic-covered mattress&lt;br&gt;
in a brick-walled building that I  &lt;br&gt;
will eventually learn to call home.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Please forgive me if I  &lt;br&gt;
forget to write to reassure you that I &lt;br&gt;
am in fact alive and have taken out &lt;br&gt;
my contacts for the night. I know you &lt;br&gt;
ask because you care.   &lt;/p&gt;</description><category>home</category><category>letters I never sent and never will</category><category>topographical poetry</category><guid>https://junypr.github.io/junypr-berries/posts/what-makes-a-home/</guid><pubDate>Sat, 05 Oct 2024 19:54:21 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Paint and Grease</title><link>https://junypr.github.io/junypr-berries/posts/paint-and-grease/</link><dc:creator>Alex Ding</dc:creator><description>&lt;p&gt;Accident was the yellow-black taxi stopped &lt;br&gt;
at your workshop. Heart-stopped —  &lt;br&gt;
it wasn’t my studio. Heartless  &lt;br&gt;
December snow trampled into metal chips &lt;br&gt;
under your boots. Paint chips  &lt;br&gt;
under my nails. You liked them. &lt;br&gt;
Maybe you’d like them painted. &lt;br&gt;
Chance was the storm keeping me with you.  &lt;br&gt;
No excuse. You handed me pliers,  &lt;br&gt;
a wrench. Taught me to weld like maybe I’d mend  &lt;br&gt;
your broken heart. Broken engine part.  &lt;br&gt;
Rose was the flush of your cheeks  &lt;br&gt;
when I brushed you. Breath-caught beauty, &lt;br&gt;
that in building two men  &lt;br&gt;
can be uncomfortably close. Beauty, &lt;br&gt;
in being comfortingly close. &lt;br&gt;
When the storm cleared &lt;br&gt;
you bloomed like a rose in the painting  &lt;br&gt;
I made of your crimson-navy swirls  &lt;br&gt;
indigo splatters and flecks of white.  &lt;br&gt;
In attic sunlight, gauze curtains drawn, &lt;br&gt;
you were my masterpiece. I, the mastermind.  &lt;br&gt;
Maybe I loaded the dice. Maybe weighted coins land  &lt;br&gt;
headfirst. Maybe I was sprinting headfirst &lt;br&gt;
to keep you by my side. &lt;br&gt;
And if I smelled like machine grease,  &lt;br&gt;
and you did too.  &lt;br&gt;
And if you smelled like acrylic paint,  &lt;br&gt;
and I did too. &lt;br&gt;
It would only be coincidence.    &lt;/p&gt;</description><category>art</category><category>love</category><category>machines</category><category>not autobiographical</category><category>things I write because I can</category><guid>https://junypr.github.io/junypr-berries/posts/paint-and-grease/</guid><pubDate>Sat, 05 Oct 2024 19:52:21 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>The four people you meet by the pond</title><link>https://junypr.github.io/junypr-berries/posts/the-four-people-you-meet-by-the-pond/</link><dc:creator>Alex Ding</dc:creator><description>&lt;p&gt;one. couple in worn-out jeans who'd drive a Jeep with the doors 
torn off and paint their walls lime green to piss off the neighbors. 
the man upends a bag of sandwich crumbs, shoos the ducks back their 
side of the fence with steel-toed boot stomps. simple equation: good 
fences equal good neighbors. the ducks slide underneath. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;two. mother who mistook you for a proper chinese child who learned 
their mother tongue in the crib like hers, now in college. hao ya zi. 
awkward american accent: yeah. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;three. not-man-not-woman-not-neither-maybe-all-of-the-above. cropped 
blonde hair makes them look like your colead. olive bomber jacket, lanky 
legs, might be your classmate. someone from your past. who you want to 
be in the future. they run like they're being tailed. maybe by you.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;four. young couple, not holding hands, but she bumps against him, the cuff 
of her sleek leather jacket touching his jeans. he is forgettable beyond 
belief, your eyes slide to the ducks crossing the sidewalk. her black hair 
is pulled into a stubby ponytail, she looks like the photos of you. you 
follow. you never see her face, but you don't want to, you think. in case 
she looks like you.&lt;/p&gt;</description><category>home</category><category>musings on an ordinary day</category><category>strangers</category><guid>https://junypr.github.io/junypr-berries/posts/the-four-people-you-meet-by-the-pond/</guid><pubDate>Sat, 05 Oct 2024 19:49:49 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>It's fall</title><link>https://junypr.github.io/junypr-berries/posts/its-fall/</link><dc:creator>Alex Ding</dc:creator><description>&lt;p&gt;My mother said the changing autumn leaves filled her with melancholy &lt;br&gt;
perhaps that is why she chose California  &lt;br&gt;
where summer slips into winter in ever dimming shades of green  &lt;br&gt;
like a photo drained of color until nothing is left but grey &lt;br&gt;
so smoothly that one never stops to realize the moment  &lt;br&gt;
in which what was had is no longer what you have   &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But here I hurtle towards the brink of winter &lt;br&gt;
desperate to hold onto these last moments in the sun   &lt;br&gt;
watching it sink through my open window  &lt;br&gt;
so painfully aware of what I have  &lt;br&gt;
and am soon to lose &lt;br&gt;
it falls.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So I watch sunlight illuminate patches of a bride's dress &lt;br&gt;
pinkies reaching, interlocking, a wedding ring  &lt;br&gt;
hands pressed palm to palm, a girl speaks Spanish on the phone  &lt;br&gt;
a blushing leaf flutters like a yellow swallowtail &lt;br&gt;
the toddler doesn't quite catch it &lt;br&gt;
it falls.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The breeze swirls the leaves like a painter's brush  &lt;br&gt;
I want to dance a dance of grief   &lt;br&gt;
sun over the Charles glows golden through the clouds  &lt;br&gt;
and warm on the back of my neck  &lt;br&gt;
crabapple nestled in the leaves &lt;br&gt;
it falls. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I observe like I did this morning through glass &lt;br&gt;
when the face I saw while folding laundry smiled back and waved &lt;br&gt;
and I tried to catch him on the stairs but was too late &lt;br&gt;
I see you. I know you.&lt;br&gt;
I am here. I tell myself I belong. &lt;br&gt;
it's fall. &lt;/p&gt;</description><category>autumn</category><category>just waiting for the seasonal affective disorder to set in</category><category>topographical poetry</category><guid>https://junypr.github.io/junypr-berries/posts/its-fall/</guid><pubDate>Sat, 05 Oct 2024 19:44:07 GMT</pubDate></item></channel></rss>