<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../assets/xml/rss.xsl" media="all"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>junypr berries (Posts about just waiting for the seasonal affective disorder to set in)</title><link>https://junypr.github.io/junypr-berries/</link><description></description><atom:link href="https://junypr.github.io/junypr-berries/categories/just-waiting-for-the-seasonal-affective-disorder-to-set-in.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"></atom:link><language>en</language><copyright>Contents © 2024 &lt;a href="mailto:alex.e.ding@gmail.com"&gt;Alex Ding&lt;/a&gt; </copyright><lastBuildDate>Sun, 06 Oct 2024 02:09:05 GMT</lastBuildDate><generator>Nikola (getnikola.com)</generator><docs>http://blogs.law.harvard.edu/tech/rss</docs><item><title>It's fall</title><link>https://junypr.github.io/junypr-berries/posts/its-fall/</link><dc:creator>Alex Ding</dc:creator><description>&lt;p&gt;My mother said the changing autumn leaves filled her with melancholy &lt;br&gt;
perhaps that is why she chose California  &lt;br&gt;
where summer slips into winter in ever dimming shades of green  &lt;br&gt;
like a photo drained of color until nothing is left but grey &lt;br&gt;
so smoothly that one never stops to realize the moment  &lt;br&gt;
in which what was had is no longer what you have   &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But here I hurtle towards the brink of winter &lt;br&gt;
desperate to hold onto these last moments in the sun   &lt;br&gt;
watching it sink through my open window  &lt;br&gt;
so painfully aware of what I have  &lt;br&gt;
and am soon to lose &lt;br&gt;
it falls.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So I watch sunlight illuminate patches of a bride's dress &lt;br&gt;
pinkies reaching, interlocking, a wedding ring  &lt;br&gt;
hands pressed palm to palm, a girl speaks Spanish on the phone  &lt;br&gt;
a blushing leaf flutters like a yellow swallowtail &lt;br&gt;
the toddler doesn't quite catch it &lt;br&gt;
it falls.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The breeze swirls the leaves like a painter's brush  &lt;br&gt;
I want to dance a dance of grief   &lt;br&gt;
sun over the Charles glows golden through the clouds  &lt;br&gt;
and warm on the back of my neck  &lt;br&gt;
crabapple nestled in the leaves &lt;br&gt;
it falls. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I observe like I did this morning through glass &lt;br&gt;
when the face I saw while folding laundry smiled back and waved &lt;br&gt;
and I tried to catch him on the stairs but was too late &lt;br&gt;
I see you. I know you.&lt;br&gt;
I am here. I tell myself I belong. &lt;br&gt;
it's fall. &lt;/p&gt;</description><category>autumn</category><category>just waiting for the seasonal affective disorder to set in</category><category>topographical poetry</category><guid>https://junypr.github.io/junypr-berries/posts/its-fall/</guid><pubDate>Sat, 05 Oct 2024 19:44:07 GMT</pubDate></item></channel></rss>