<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../assets/xml/rss.xsl" media="all"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>junypr berries (Posts about prose)</title><link>https://junypr.github.io/junypr-berries/</link><description></description><atom:link href="https://junypr.github.io/junypr-berries/categories/prose.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"></atom:link><language>en</language><copyright>Contents © 2024 &lt;a href="mailto:alex.e.ding@gmail.com"&gt;Alex Ding&lt;/a&gt; </copyright><lastBuildDate>Wed, 23 Oct 2024 00:11:54 GMT</lastBuildDate><generator>Nikola (getnikola.com)</generator><docs>http://blogs.law.harvard.edu/tech/rss</docs><item><title>Part-time Father</title><link>https://junypr.github.io/junypr-berries/posts/part-time-father/</link><dc:creator>Alex Ding</dc:creator><description>&lt;p&gt;I was five when you left for the first time. Not the two-week business-trip and visiting-family kind of leaving. Not leaving for good, either. You were there one bleak morning, waving goodbye to me through the security lines, steel-gray suitcase and backpack in hand, then gone. House empty. Peaceful.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At first, you and mother call every night. Then every week. Then almost never. The whispers become more like empty screams and I think I hear the phone ring, my mother not picking up, your voice calling for me, me not picking up. I don’t like hearing the screams. I can’t make out the words, but I know what screaming means.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We visited your Shanghai apartment that summer, and I remember the drip of chocolate-dipped ice cream cones, the fan thinly fighting the heat, the plastic covering of the bed that wasn’t my own. I dreamed that blood was pouring from every pore in my skin that night, into the fabric of a foreign-not-foreign country that I can and can’t call my home.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;I was seven when you made the business arrangement. Half your year here, with us, half your year there, in the country I knew in my blood but had never seen. Part-time father, my brother called it. I didn’t know what part-time meant. Or maybe he didn’t.&lt;/em&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;I draw sketches of you from faded yellow photos, to give when you return. Mother says I’m quite good. A natural-born artist.&lt;/em&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When you come back you bring a suitcase full of gifts. Snacks. I like the thin not-mint hawthorne candies and the rolls of fruit leather in little plastic packages with words I cannot read. You give me a pencil sharpener. It could sharpen a finger. I don’t know why it says “a little girl and boy” on it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You take me to the department store, and I fidget through hours of escalator rides and check-out lines. You buy a cardboard “A” for me. For the race I am and the grades I am supposed to get — except you forget that I am in kindergarten and do not have those kinds of grades yet. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;When you are home, you wake me up with a steaming mug of coffee in hand, and drive me to school before returning home to work. When you’re not home, my alarm forgets to wake me up on time. I arrive at math late and groggy, sky-blue thermos of instant coffee in hand.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While you’re gone, we find out that my passport needs renewing. You go to the consulate in Shanghai to get an affidavit notarized, except you’ve gotten my name wrong. It’s Emily, not Emma. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My mom calls for the first time in weeks, and you make a second trip. I hope you’re properly embarrassed. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;I learn to play the violin. You don’t like my drawings.&lt;/em&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am in middle school and have a poster of a NASA facility on my door, torn out from a magazine. I line my shelves with lego helicopters and 3D prints of robots I clumsily designed. You give me pink unicorn tape and an electric trash can whose lid opens like the jaws of a steel hippo at the push of a button. I can’t figure out how to turn it off and I don’t know why you couldn’t have gotten one with a pedal. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You ask me what I want to do, and I say, “physics.” You tell me about your childhood, exaggerating your class ranking. I’ve stopped listening after the third time. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You say the haircut I gave myself is ugly and my face needs washing. You ask me when I am going to get a boyfriend. Then you ask when I’m going to get married. I think you forget I’m in middle school. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;I’m happy when you’re home, but I can’t pretend everything’s alright. You ask my brother how he enjoys tennis and forget that he is still recovering from a broken wrist that happened a few weeks after you left. He doesn’t say anything, but I can sense his retreat. He digs trenches and throws barbed wire around himself.&lt;/em&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the mornings, when you’re here, you make yourself a mug of overly-sweetened coffee, until the smell permeates every scrap of wood and I think I’ll never get rid of it. I try to avoid having breakfast with you, but I’m too tired to wake up early and too tired to listen to my mom yell at me for getting up so late. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I don’t like dinner.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;My brother goes to college, and suddenly you’re awakened to his academic mediocrity. I guess you never realized that, with your absences, until he’s packing for a mid-level public school and you’ve become the joke of your ex-pat parties.&lt;/em&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;The pressure’s on me, the only child in the house. Mother tries to shield me, but she can’t stop the barrage. Art is a waste, computer science is the only option. I'm dropped out of the painting class I love. Now it’s not good enough to play the violin. Now I have to be the best in the state. I play until my fingers callus, then bleed, then callus again. I didn’t even know that was possible.&lt;/em&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;You tell me that I’m not going to waste my life partying and studying statistics like my brother.&lt;/em&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There’s rats in the attic and leaking pipes in the walls but you’ve never bothered to ask how we’re fixing it. The house is your hotel. You walk on carpets with muddy shoes, leave the door open until the hallways are full of dust and flies, and leave us to clean up once you’re gone. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Dinner conversations are empty. You lecture me on your successes in drugs to fight cancer but never remember the projects I’m working on. You think I should be a doctor. I know better. Look at what you did to my brother and sister.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You insist on salmon or steak every night, as if you’ve been starved in China. I grow tired of the dry flesh and lock myself in my room. I find solace in music.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;My brother’s pierced his ears, grown his hair long, and is taking a liking to sky-blue bomber jackets over hoodies and dyed hair. He looks different every time he comes back. I like it. You don’t. Mother blames you for it. Lack of a strong male presence and all. I think she wants a divorce.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Except I’m in the house still, and I’m too busy to waste time worrying.&lt;/em&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;We meet at a summer camp. You have no idea what we’re doing. You pretend you’re proud but we know you’re not. We track vanishingly faint asteroids in the sky and realize that we are not alone. Not in the universe, not in our predicament. We’re free.&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;It’s a nice feeling.&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We move and I slam doors in this old-new house and when my mother asks me why, all I can say is that you keep me up at night, listening to videos without headphones in your study next door, stomping around. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It’s true. It’s been true for a long time. I can’t really articulate why I hate you.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;When I return home and that beautiful, blessed freedom is taken away from me, I shut myself in my room and cry for a long time. I’m alone. I’m one single speck of dust dropped into the velvety black infinite.&lt;/em&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;I keep in touch with my friends from camp. They know how I’m feeling. One contacts my mother, who tries to talk to me. But she can’t stop you. I hear raised voices. You think I can’t understand Chinese, but I do. And you say “divorce” in English anyway.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You don’t know that it’s college application season for me, but you act like you’ve been waiting for it your whole life. Except the only question you ask is if I’m applying to an Ivy League. And the only response I can give is yes. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You don’t know what my dream school is, and you don’t know that I got in. And I’m glad to be going a long, long ways away from home. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He tells me that his mother’s made it final. She’s keeping the house. He’s been accepted. And he, too, is glad to be going a long, long ways away from home. &lt;/p&gt;</description><category>a collection of experiences from my life and friend's</category><category>prose</category><category>short story</category><guid>https://junypr.github.io/junypr-berries/posts/part-time-father/</guid><pubDate>Wed, 23 Oct 2024 00:09:25 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>The Thing About Sunsets</title><link>https://junypr.github.io/junypr-berries/posts/the-thing-about-sunsets/</link><dc:creator>Alex Ding</dc:creator><description>&lt;p&gt;Each sunset is a fragile fraction of a moment suspended in time like a mote of dust in a sunbeam. 
Each day brings a new palette, daubs of inimitable hand-mixed paint swirls. 
So I grab my camera and fly down the stairs, 
I don't stop to say hello because something inside my chest tells me that this is what matters, 
that I need to be here, 
breath catching in the crisp fall air as I watch the last glimmers of sunlight fade over the Charles 
and burnish the glass skyscrapers of Boston's skyline gold. 
Something within me finds peace as my eyes ascend the gradient of soft pink blushes and orange streaks into the wash of 
cyan above. Something tells me that I must hold onto this the way I cling to the rail's flaking paint. 
Something tells me this beauty will never be repeated.
Whether this moment brings me joy or brings me to my knees, 
whether the shimmer is fool's gold or true, 
I have only this moment. 
Like sunsets, nothing lasts forever. 
What is there to be done but to enjoy it?&lt;/p&gt;</description><category>prose</category><category>random thoughts</category><category>sunsets</category><guid>https://junypr.github.io/junypr-berries/posts/the-thing-about-sunsets/</guid><pubDate>Tue, 22 Oct 2024 23:56:30 GMT</pubDate></item></channel></rss>